Abhishek Aggarwal

Software Developer - Data Analyst - Blogger

I am an enthusiastic, responsible and hardworking IT professional. Having worked for different projects has helped me to adapt to the changes quickly and made me a mature team worker who can work under pressure and adhere to strict deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

July 2019 - PRESENT

Tata Consultancy Services, Noida — Systems Engineer

As a system engineer in TCS, I had worked on different domains including **Satellite Image Processing**, **Deep Learning**, **Computer Vision** etc. I was also responsible for working closely with the UI team and developing a platform for General Surveillance which includes **Face detection & Recognition**, **Person Tracking and liveness detection**.

July 2018 - September 2018

Netcamp Solutions, Ghaziabad — *Internship*

During the internship, I was trained in **Web Development, Android App Development and Networking Concepts** and henceforth given projects to be completed within deadline.

Tools Used: VMware, Redhat Linux, Cisco Packet Tracer, Android Studio, Wamp Server.

PUBLICATIONS

5th June 2020 – 7th June 2020

Comparative Assessment of Different Deep Learning Models for Aircraft Detection

2020 International Conference for Emerging Technology (INCET)

Headed a research on the comparative study of three models – (YOLOv3, SSD and RCNN) for small scale object detection like aircraft on satellite images and presented it to IEEE Bangalore in INCET 2020 conference.



15th September 1997 (23, Male)



91, Opposite Power House, Niwari Road Modinagar, Pin 201204



(+91) 8267827798



abhishekaggarwal314@gmail.com



github.com/aggarwal-abhishek



linked.com/in/aggarwal-abhishek

SKILLS

Operating System: Linux, Windows

Data Structures (C++, JAVA)

Version Control Git

Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, PyTorch, Keras, Scikit-learn, Flask, Jupyter Notebook)

Tools (Anaconda Framework, VSCode, Android Studio, Vim)

Machine Learning, Data Analysis

Computer Vision, Face Recognition, Object Detection

Docker, ElasticSearch, Kibana

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng: Completed various courses on Deep learning in this specialization on Coursera ranging from Simple neural networks to CNN and Sequence Models.

Awarded with a title of CodeStar during Farewell at Raj Kumar Goel Institute of Technology in May, 2019.

Yellow coder on Codechef: Acquired a global rank of 130 among more than 11000 participants in codechef during September 2018.

TCS Codevita: 28th Rank in TCS codevita coding platform in August 2018

PROJECTS

September 2020 - December 2020

Semantic Search - Intelligent Site Analysis

- As a part of Decision Fabric Platform in TCS, I was responsible for developing a Semantic Search Engine in close collaboration with a Life Science's Customer.
- The project aims at providing user-friendly search capabilities
 on the customer's enterprise data with intelligent site
 analysis with the help of Decision Fabric Analytical
 components.
- Various other tools like ElasticSearch, Kibana, Docker etc. were leveraged to develop and deploy the application in the production environment.

June 2020 - August 2020

Intelligent Face Detection & Recognition System along with Liveness Check

- Face detection using OpenCV and then using Dlib to get facial features embedding vectors.
- Using that embedding vector to recognize the person in a video live stream.
- Detecting various features like eye blinking and head movement in order to check liveness of a person in live camera footage.

February 2020 - June 2020

Video Analytics for Personal Safety during Pandemic Times

- As a part of the Decision Fabric Platform Team in TCS, I worked closely to build a live intelligent video analytics platform to detect different people and track their inter zone movements across office premises.
- Then I also worked to leverage this solution in order to detect whether a person in a live CCTV video stream is following safety standards by wearing a mask and maintaining social distancing among other employees as well.

September 2019 – December 2019

Small scale Aircraft Detection in Satellite Images

- The main aim of this project was to **detect various aircraft in satellite images** and give the count of all aircraft present in a particular location (airport) at a particular time.
- For this Deep learning task, MobileNet SSD model was used to achieve 94% accuracy.

EDUCATION

June 2015 – June 2019

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Raj Kumar Goel Institute of Technology, Ghaziabad

Percentage: 71.7 %

April 2014 - April 2015

STANDARD XII / H.S.C. C.B.S.E. - Computer Science Major

Dayawati Modi Public School, Modinagar Percentage: 89.4 %

April 2012 - April 2013

SSC C.B.S.E.

Chhaya Public School, Modinagar CGPA: 9.2

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

STRENGTHS

Team Player, Quick learner, Flexibility, Adaptability, Goal oriented

HOBBIES

Gaming, Sports, Hackathons, Competitive Programming, Reading Books, Travelling, Listening Music